<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Dataasana</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Dataasana</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nifty Small Cap 250 - Stocks Performance</title>
      <link>/post/2019-10-21-nifty-smallcap-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-10-21-nifty-smallcap-story/</guid>
      <description>Indian stock market is in huge turmoil for last 18 to 20 months. Investors have seen lot of wealth erosion. As per majority of the super investors, they have never seen wealth erosion of this magnitude in history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Dates - Part I</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-08-lubridate-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-08-lubridate-1/</guid>
      <description>Working with dates and time is one of the important skills for a data science engineer. Lot of the datasets which we get to work on will have date attribute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading Multiple Files into a DataFrame</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-02-r-loading-multiple-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-02-r-loading-multiple-files/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick tidbit for showing how we can load multiple files with the same structure in a folder into a dataframe.
You can either read all the files separately and bind them together into one single dataframe using bind_rows() or you can do this with one line of code using one of the options below.

Option 1This is one of the slowest optiondata &amp;lt;- bind_rows(lapply(list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Map using Highcharter - World Population</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-02-r-highcharter-usa-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-02-r-highcharter-usa-maps/</guid>
      <description>Maps are wonderful visualization type for showing representing the geograhical information. I think after the bar plots, maps are the most commonly used and easily understood visualization type.
Highcharter R package provides us with very easy way of creating amazing maps. In this post we are going to learn how to create maps using this wonderful package.
Maps are used for plotting geographical data which provides more insights than using plain simple barplots or other visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barplots using Highcharter</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-02-r-highcharter-barplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-02-r-highcharter-barplots/</guid>
      <description>Bar plots are used for plotting the categorical variables distribution in the dataset with respect to count or based on summary of quantitative variable. Grouped bar plots is used specially when there are two categorical variables which we want to view the distribution.
For example:Buying price and current price of different stocks in the portfolio.
We are going to use the below mentioned dataset for plotting the grouped bar chart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Needs Kaggle</title>
      <link>/post/2019-09-01-r-kaggle-datascience-survey-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-09-01-r-kaggle-datascience-survey-story/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I am on Kaggle one of the most important things I always try to notice is where are my fellow Kagglers from. Not that I want them to be from any specific country but I am always more interested in knowing how many from developing and under developed countries are actively using the BEST DATA SCIENCE LEARNING PLATFORM IN THE WORLD to build their Data Science Skills.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>